like I wonder if the person that created
you know an inventions like 2002. yeah
it's like I can make what if I force the
user let me let me log into my bank and
see if this works you know like yeah and
that's like the original write-up you
know it's like passing around material
on the dark web like forbank.com you can
trick you know trigger transfers I don't
know why that's my voice for early day
hackers like maybe it's the early 2000s
yeah exactly
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
no Jill you're sitting man this is this
is if we're gonna if we're gonna debate
this you need to stand up okay like I
just wanted to show off my new headrest
that's all oh oh that is good looking
man you get a new chair
no no sim chirp so oh my God sorry I
have something in my mouth yeah sorry I
started it like right as you put
something into your mouth
what is it like caramel or something
like that yeah it's a chewy it's a
ginger thing anyways anyways
um this company Atlas they make like the
Herman Miller like third party headrests
and the embody headrest is better than
like pre-orders for like six months so
I ordered mine back in December and it
finally came like a week or two ago so
it's been like a huge huge nice
Improvement to an already amazing chair
so yes but that that's it I'll stand up
all right that's like the geekiest thing
I've ever you pre-ordered a headset or a
headrest for your chair there we go now
let's let's rise and let's let's debate
okay so all right all right so you say
so before we were we before we ran the
live recording Joe was saying there's no
such thing as a sea surf on mobile I
suspect this is a
terminology difference but yeah all
right so here's here's what it is all
right see surf on mobile let's say for
example I've we talked about this sort
of on the on the mobile episode
it's a like a deep link or like a uh
uh what are they called the app app
links that you can trigger that will
trigger some sort of functionality in
the in the app so for example if I have
like if I can craft a link that like has
I've seen this before has like a base64
encoded you know data blob in it and
that file gets like downloaded and put
onto the user's device or something like
that and you know that that's not the
perfect most perfect example maybe it's
something on the lines of like add
friend you know equals one two three
four and then like when you click that
link you automatically send them a
friend request right I feel like that's
a mobile c-surf is that not
I mean so like yes and no I think to
some extent you could count that as a c
surf but it's not really like in the
classical sense if you think about what
a sea surf is like a sea surface a
cross-site request forgery right and so
okay okay Joel like it's not a site come
on but it's an app well yeah but it's
not a site but it's also like
there is no restriction that you can put
in place to like stop this like if you
click a deep link for example like you
said if I click a deep link for my
browser nothing that gets passed through
tells the app that I clicked that from
attacker.com okay okay but but like you
could just not write functionality where
someone can have a deep link that does
something in the app unvalidated like
there should be a screen that pops up
and says are you sure you want to add
you know Jimmy gym as a friend
uh yeah sure but like how do you detect
that
well no there's no detection so like the
reality is that like if you don't want
this to be a thing it has to be not
exposed at all like that functioning
functionality cannot exist right if you
want uh for somebody to be able to add a
friend either you have to have a
separate x a separate route that is
exposed that's like add friend confirm
and then like when they click that then
the app does different functionality
where they confirm it explicitly but the
fact that that deep link exists means
that it will always be reachable if it's
if it's exposed so either it can't be
exposed or you have to you know or okay
it's it either is or it isn't so so what
you're saying is like even though that
functionality you're saying there's no
way to make it that functionality secure
if you want to have that functionality
is that what you're saying yeah and so I
think like the caveat to this and the
bug that I picked as like an example for
this I think the the best caveat I can
think of is like JavaScript Bridges so
that's like kind of the closest you can
get to like a sea surf type of behavior
where say like within a browser within a
webview within the app you are able to
either call out to a different uh
internal only
URL yeah or Java a JavaScript Bridge or
something like that to trigger
functionality within the app from an
attacker website that is something that
you can stop you can detect origin and
stuff from a JavaScript Bridge you can
do all that kind of stuff but if you
know it's just the fact that the Deep
link exists and is callable externally I
wouldn't really call that a sea surf so
much as an abusive intended
functionality okay um so maybe that's my
it's not like blockable maybe that's my
like web brain trying to apply it to
mobile that's like the way that I've
categorized it in my head to try to get
you know it to fit into my little
context you know yeah so I could see
that but I I am a little disappointed
though because I definitely wanted there
to be carf
cross app request surgery like I feel
like carf we could we could just like
yeah can you like make that kind of
exists too okay I mean like is that a
real thing yeah so I think like that's
also a thing for example like intense
right if like you create an intent from
right yeah right and you call an intent
like that's going across app but
you know and you can stop that stuff
just like you can with the sea surf but
do you remember that bug from at uh in
LA
yeah that that was I feel like that's
kind of like a carf am I right
yeah yeah I would say that that's pretty
that's like a pretty good example of
like a cross app request foreign
yeah yeah it's I mean it's basically and
that I think is a really common
exploitation scenario with within mobile
apps yeah and it totally breaks CVSs
because it's like local only
um because like you need another app on
the system yeah to be exploitable yeah
but
um but yeah no that's like a really
common thing where you have some
functionality that's you know accessible
from other apps on the system that is
then exploitable to
do all sorts of different functionality
that I mean we've seen full rce from
that so yeah you can go anywhere from
Super basic stuff to full RC where's our
um where's our notes on the mobile
episode because isn't there like so like
for example if you're doing like a carf
right and you need to craft like an
intent there are the intent URLs though
right that you can like almost embed it
into a URL and it like still sends the
intent
yeah if I recall correctly that is no
longer supported in like Chrome and
chromium I believe it was like a it's an
older Android thing and it's up to like
implementation essentially about whether
or not it's supported
um
but I might be wrong yeah I'm looking
back through the notes well we'll have
to find that and assess it later
yeah
all right cool well
that's our nice little debate to start
us off today whether or not mobile
c-surfs exist or whether carf is a thing
cross apps yeah
man all right yeah you know what that's
going to be I'm
gonna send out a tweet right after after
this episode carf is a thing that's all
I'm gonna say perfect no context yeah no
contacts just carf is a thing
cool
um all right man uh let's let's get back
to the news yeah
all right yeah for sure let's see
news is looking up I'm not gonna lie man
news was a little bit thin this week
um yeah I think it's just stuff's
leading up to Defcon yeah we're holding
their cards close to their chest they
don't want to let everything fall just
yet but I don't doubt that I would
recommend within like two weeks we're
gonna have some really crazy amounts of
news that we're gonna have to go through
yeah dude are you gonna are you gonna
try to do like any
Joel solo episodes at Defcon you think
or at the h1702 event
um I might I'm not gonna be at Defcon
I'm only gonna be at the H1 event so
um we'll see whether or not anybody
wants to do like some recording sessions
I'm trying to yeah grab like an extra
handheld mic that I can yeah that'd be
good use is sort of like an interview
type thing
um that I wouldn't feel bad about
traveling with like this mic I probably
wouldn't travel with because it's
expensive and if something happened
during travel I would be be very sad
about it myself yeah yeah no I believe
that man I I think I just think the
in-person interviews have such a good
vibe you know with cosmin and and with
uh you know mystery guest we did record
a few episodes when we were in London
one of them hasn't been cleared for
release yet so we've got an awesome
episode in the back lot that you guys
are really going to enjoy
um but yeah I feel like those were sick
so if we can do more of those that would
be really good I think yeah yeah I do
plan on bringing the recorder so we'll
uh we'll we'll definitely see hopefully
I'll get at least one in there all right
so the first news item on the list day
was actually something that that rezzo
tweeted out like a couple minutes before
we started recording and I was like oh
we should just throw this in there
um he says here's a bug bounding tip
that I just learned from TCM Securities
YouTube live stream SQL map can use the
same syntax as curl so if you do copy as
curl in any tool paste it into a
terminal exchange curl to SQL map it
just works
that's crazy
SQL map also lets you do like raw
request inputs it does so you can
literally just that's one of my favorite
features is you can basically just copy
paste a full raw HTTP request into a
text file and then you just yeah SQL map
yeah I think so and then it just parses
it and it will do all the magic you
don't have to set a different flag for
cookies or any of that kind of stuff so
yeah it's awesome I want to see
I want to say fuff also does route
request doesn't it I believe it does
yeah
yeah it does dash request file
containing the raw HTTP request I love
that man that's so helpful yeah I mean
it just makes it so much easier for
testing when you when you don't have to
look up all the different flags and if
you like run it once and something's not
working or maybe it looks like it's
working but it's not actually working
just knowing that for sure it's using
the exact request that you were using
makes it so much easier to do your
testing yeah and easy to in insert
insertion points both an SQL map and fav
but you know it is very convenient when
you've got a curl request as well or
when you're for example if you're
finding an SQL if you're one of those
freaks that finds sqls if I adjust the
freaking
um uh inspector tool then you know you
can right click and copy the curl on
this I will say the first the first SQL
injection I ever found was using uh uh
what is it hack hack bar Hacker no way
oh my God way back in the day I cannot
believe that man uh extension dude I
just got like freaking teleported back
to like early college man hack bar are
you serious hack bar yeah I think that
that's what it was called right yeah
yeah I just I just looked it up it's
still a thing it seems like they've
actually added some pretty cool features
to it
that's really cool that's pretty sick
man a lot of reviews too 50 000 plus
users this is a good this is a good
extension it's so crazy this is not
related to security stuff but I heard I
heard someone on on a podcast the other
day talk about marketing a product by
buying Chrome extensions for like like
one cent per user right really yeah so
they're buying like you know 40 000 plus
install apps for like 400 bucks you know
and it's like
wow I don't know how you even Market to
it I guess maybe you'd like do some sort
of invasive little pop-up ad thing you
know push code to it but that I don't
know man yeah that's really interesting
I wonder like if that violates any of
the Chrome web store rules I know that
like when you uninstall an extension
there's like a report this extension
type thing and I don't actually know if
I've ever reported an extension but I'm
I assume they ask for more info about
like why you're reporting it so what you
got to do is get the Chrome extension
use the Chrome extension to install a
service worker on that page and just
automatically say no to that
yeah just take over their computer
actually that's like a that's an
interesting
I I don't think I feel like Chrome
extensions shouldn't be able to
install service workers on specific
sites right I don't know I gotta look at
it might be a specific permission
because even when you install one you
have to Grant it specific like site by
site like whatever it's requesting
access to so okay yeah that makes it I
gotta look into that though that would
be that'd be a fun attack vector
yeah
um there was this uh there was this
tweet you made today actually where you
were like uh I'm so annoyed like when
you find an eye door and your sessions
get swapped so I wrote this JS
bookmarklet that puts a cookie on the
TLD of the Target and then I use request
highlighter to highlight each yeah
browser a different color and I do that
as well by the way yeah um that's like
thank you that makes me feel a little
bit I have for like two-person testing
is I have an incognito window and I have
a normal window in the same browser and
I just you know do a the request
highlighter uh extension to highlight
different colors for those two sessions
if it's like really really complicated
and I have them both open at the same
time but if it's something super
straightforward I'll usually just like
copy paste my off header or whatever it
is yeah yeah I that's what so that's
what I do and then like a couple people
from the freaking like Twitter went on
here and we're like yo there's already
extensions to do this and yeah
apparently one of the is so there's burp
browser profiles there's Auto Chrome I
think is the other one there's what was
the one that they said something
yeah that's what it is and actually I
clicked on the phone pop or phone Fox
one I can't say it I clicked on the
phone Fox one and it looks pretty sick
like if you look at the highlighting
within that looks really good so
definitely could be worth using but you
know if you're using Firefox yuck
way lower than I would have expected
same
um but actually ponefox also lists uh
listen to read me that if you're using
Chrome you can use this NCC group Tool
called Auto Chrome Auto Chrome yeah
which does a lot of like default setups
and stuff
I used to do something very similar to
this where I had a shortcut like an
alias in my terminal that I would use to
spin up a new Chrome instance that would
run like without the xss auditor and
would have the proxy args and all that
kind of stuff
nowadays it's so easy to proxy Chrome
and I really don't want the xss auditor
turned off if I'm being honest because
well it doesn't do anything anymore
like and it's such it's such like a a
bar in terms of like if something is
getting caught by the exercise auditor
which I like you're saying I don't
actually know if it does anything
anymore yeah then I probably don't want
to submit that because there what's the
attack scenario where somebody has xss
auditor disabled and I'm able to exploit
their Chrome I feel like xss auditor got
removed and the only case that I can
think of that it actually I'm not sure
if this is xss auditor if it's something
else but is like when you you click a
link that has Target equals
um blank
uh on it right so it's supposed to open
up a new tab and that your injection is
in that href right then I think it says
no can't do that
um I was just looking it's been fully
removed as of chrome 78. that's so
clutch man like I I do remember for a
brief period when that was around and
it's just like please like just please
stop like you know that I can bypass you
like please just don't make me do it you
know
yeah for sure hold on one second my
dog's barking yeah
so did you see this JS weasel thing that
got released earlier this week
I didn't see it get released but I saw
it in the notes and when I clicked into
it I was like really kind of Blown Away
by like I mean one I I think I'd like
toyed around with something like an idea
like this for the longest time like
everyone has
yeah yeah and it's really really cool to
see it pop up
um I was like who created this and I did
like some digging it was Charlie it was
created by Charlie Erickson yeah um he's
pretty big in the bug Bounty Community I
don't I'm sure a lot of people kind of
know who he is or have heard his name he
is definitely very active in bug Manny
Forum yeah that's where I know him and
yeah that's where I know him from as
well uh it looks like he's kind of done
a bunch of startup stuff in the past uh
based on his like Twitter bio and stuff
um I hadn't realized all these like
companies and stuff that he'd done so
it's a really cool product to see uh
kind of pop up I would love to try it
out yeah I saw the price that I don't
really want I got my hands on it I got
my hands on oh did you I did yes he he
um he actually sent me the beta for it
like oh cool months ago and I was like
wow this is sick like I gotta talk about
this on the podcast and we decided to
hold off at the time because you know it
was just kind of a beta mode he was
going to do a release around Defcon on
but now is the time to talk about it man
and I have to say like the price is high
for sure like a thousand dollars per
user per year
that's pricey man that's pricey and I
feel like he kind of needs a like a
freemium of this you know like I feel
like he needs to to release some part of
it that's free and then you know or
maybe even like a short trial to get you
hooked on it because it's hard to take
the bite to go straight into a thousand
dollar a year product
um yeah however
even the beta version that I played
around with was pretty freaking sick
like it was it was quite good and um
he's added a lot of features since then
the one that kind of blows me away the
most go to go to the website right
yep and go to features
um in the in the tab scroll down and
then look at the fetch packed chunks
right he says uh yeah yeah so I think I
feel like everyone who's who's ever like
deep dived a Javascript file uh or
anyone who does that on a regular basis
will know what this looks like uh
essentially it's a function that will
you know has a specific like name it's
normally like it number colon you know
name you know three colon PDF make seven
colon XLS and then there's another block
and then there's a dot in that and then
it has a bunch of hashes and then at the
end it has dot JS so just from looking
at it you can clearly see their
um loading they're constructing what a
normal JS file looks like with like the
hash and then the dash and then the
actual name of whatever it is dot dot JS
or whatever right
um and so I time and time again have
written scripts to decode this and get
me access to these JavaScript files that
are being apparently he they're they're
being lazy loaded that's what that the
technical term is for that like loaded
you know sort of dynamically uh on the
fly when needed and so if you never
access you know the weird admin part of
the application that actually loads it
then you'll never actually get the
contents of that JS file you know in
your browser but right JS weasel somehow
parses the JS code that does this
figures out how to maybe there's like a
common structure to it or something
figures out how to reverse this and Auto
download those JS files which is really
sick
yeah it's super interesting I would be
really really curious to see how good it
does especially with same obfuscated and
minified JavaScript I think that's
generally the case where I
find stuff has the biggest difficulty
just generally like any sort of like
parsing tool whether it's symbol
recognition or anything like that
obfuscated JavaScript generally throws a
real big wrench into that I don't it
seems like it was kind of designed
JavaScript that much though like I mean
obviously you could just get literally
just a Target I was looking at yesterday
uses obfuscated job like obfuscated and
minified oh my gosh dude that's how I
thought it was malware at first it was
actually a blown away I thought it was
malware that's good yeah no I I mean I
feel like maybe one in 50 targets that I
look at use actual obfuscated JavaScript
which for any of you blue teamers out
there uh that is a Surefire way to piss
off uh anyone who's trying to hack your
app if there's like if I if all of your
strings in the app are in HEX
Frick you like I I hate that like
so yeah 100 yeah
um I I definitely I'd like to get my
hands on the latest version I'm kind of
even even you know with bug Bounty being
my full thing and you know pulling in a
decent amount each year with with money
to allocate to tools and stuff like that
I don't know man I don't know if it's
worth the one 1K but I might see if I
can figure out but I also don't blame
him for anchoring High you know like
yeah it would be better if he like
framed it like you know 75 a month or
something like that because I think
what's a thousand divided by 12 is yeah
83 dollars a month yeah like if it was
83 a month I might be more willing to
click it instead of seeing a thousand
dollars a year per user something like
that and I totally agree like you got to
make a profit somehow like work isn't
free
um but I think if you look generally at
like the bug Bounty community and
so many tools are free and or have like
a trial or something like that like
there's very few tools that bug bounty
hunters pay for yeah absolutely and so I
think having a uh something that's
useful like this that you have to pay
for and having it at such a high bar
might be difficult to get bug Bounty
people to get on board with that you
could probably sell it for like a
quarter of this and get five times as
many people signing up oh yeah a lot so
there's there's probably some sort of
like tweaking he's he's gonna have to do
with that pricing and all that kind of
stuff but in terms of like product and
functionality and features this looks
really amazing yeah dude I'm excited I
hope the price does come down a little
bit because I would definitely use this
um there's definitely you know product
Market fit here with um you know the
burp Suite plug-in
um and you know it's pushing right into
this app that's how it works by the way
for any of you that that aren't at the
website it you have a burp Suite plug-in
it shoves everything down to a vs code
plugin that um just sucks it all up
beautifies it adds a bunch of really
cool
um JS highlighting and uh like you know
various layers of of pulling stuff out
notified it'll deal with Source Maps
it'll deal with obfuscated JavaScript
it'll deal with chunks like
um so yeah it's really interesting it's
funny because whenever I do JavaScript
audits I have like my own internal like
brain system that I use where like I
figured out certain patterns that I
notice within uh obscated or minified
JavaScript or webpack JavaScript
whatever you want to call it and those
I'll like use those patterns to identify
how stuff is working but I never really
go further than that I never end up like
writing scripts okay I just like I see
like my interests what are these
internal brain patterns yeah so like
there's this like one thing that I
notice a lot where webpack stuff they'll
often when stuff gets packed together
into one giant file they'll name all the
modules as numbers like incremental
numbers so that they'll be like you know
module one which was actually FS or
something is now one and then there'll
be some function called like n and it'll
be like ends with an argument one and
then you know that it's it's importing
like module numbers I know what you're
talking about you can search backwards
and so you can say like okay where is
the module with like one colon like
where is that in the in the module
dictionary and then you can go and find
the source and you can figure out what
module is what yeah
and that's kind of like the system that
I've always used but this feels so much
cleaner and more organized and more
concrete than that and I think it would
probably make for a lot less guesswork
if it really works the way that it
claims it does so yeah yeah this is a
really really awesome and I I also like
that the website looks just like a like
a GitHub product launcher oh it does it
really
it really does yeah oh yeah with the big
with the big text right with one word
you know highlighted it's true exactly
you're not wrong man that's a good
that's a good call
um all right let's see what else we got
um
okay uh the only other thing that I
really had on the list today was this uh
like literally right before we started
recording freaking rojin tweeted out uh
a
uh link to a talk that they had done at
Tinder security Labs
um about an RC in various Services uh
via largely via GitHub actions workflows
and excluding those which is like pretty
much the most Rogen thing I've ever
heard in my life right like he always
goes after this like out there
you know bespoke stuff and uh and so
yeah I don't know did you did you see
this at all because I actually didn't
get the chance to actually uh check out
the talk I just clicked through the
slides before we launched the yeah I
didn't I didn't really get to check it
out
um it's kind of crazy I don't know if I
should say but
maybe we'll cut this out yeah I work
with Rojan right right and uh you know
he's all he's always doing really
amazing research so it's cool to see
some of this go public
um and see it be talked about sort of on
a more public stage yeah for sure all
the internal Communications that we have
about it
um but yeah I mean Rojan is obviously a
very very talented hacker
um him and all the other people that uh
that we have on our team are just
some of the best like bug Bounty folks
as well as just hackers as a whole that
that uh that I know and so it's really
awesome to have them on the team and see
them do this kind of research and then
you actually get to talk about it
publicly at conferences yeah dude not
gonna lie um I'm I'm jealous of y'all's
y'all's team over there rojin hit me up
the other day about wow this is a while
back actually about an opening on
y'all's team and I was like yep shoot
man like if there's anything to pull me
away from freaking full-time bug Bounty
it would be a full-time research role on
that team and I was like ah
so yeah I mean I was just reading
through one of their internal reports
today and it's very like I think you
would it would enjoy it if oh my God
yeah there was another opportunity that
came up I think it would be something
that would totally be your Vibe because
it's literally just like
hacking it's just yeah heck man that
yeah that sounds awesome so we'll link
this this report down in the uh in the
description for the podcast or this um I
guess these slides and and YouTube video
talk
um yeah should be some really high
quality content also I just I love
injecting into the supply chain right
rather than doing other stuff you know
later after the product's been pushed
anything with like dependency confusion
attacking the continuous integration
pipeline all of that stuff super cool
and I happen to know a couple other
players in the space that are getting
ready to launch products or will be
launching products within the next year
surrounding this that I think are going
to really be very helpful
yeah so yeah actually now that I'm I'm
looking through all of uh all the slides
on this yeah yes I did know a little bit
about this yeah yeah but seeing seeing
the slides and seeing it like talked
about
definitely gives you a lot more context
than than what I had so I'm gonna have
to check out the the actual video of the
talk later yeah for sure I'll go I'll go
watch this as well
um all right as as we alluded to in the
beginning of this episode with our
debate
um we are talking about sea surfs today
uh and yeah essentially I feel like sea
surf is a vulnerability that a lot of
people feel like got deleted with
same-site cookies and it's just not the
case and there are some
you know stringent conditions that you
got to be on the lookout for but I still
see this all the time on all levels of
hardenedness of Target
um
so I was thinking we'd kind of dive into
that today discuss some techniques that
we've seen just have some technicalities
and see where it takes us
yeah yeah 100
alrighty let's see
um okay so first thing that I kind of
wanted to talk about was for any of you
that that
are out there that haven't heard of a
sea surf let's just go ahead and give a
little a little bit of a debrief for
that that is cross-site request forgery
um this attack occurs when the victim
clicks on the link from the attacker the
attacker has control views there's
browser inside of the the page and the
attacker
um somehow either by doing a window.open
or by doing a redirect or submitting a
HTML form is able to push the user via
redirection to some specific page on the
victim application
um you know it could be a get request or
it could be a post request and that that
request will trigger some sort of
functionality in that application and
perform some action on behalf of the
user since that request is being done
with the user's cookies
um and yeah go ahead yeah well I was
just gonna say I think like the most
like basic example that I can think of
just going back to like my very very
early security days was
bank account the the typical example is
that you are using bank.com and there's
a transfer endpoint that you can call to
transfer money from your account to
someone else's account and if there's a
c surf there then another website could
force you to call that transfer endpoint
using your own cookies in your own
session and transfer money somewhere
else and if there's no C serp check then
that could happen completely without
anybody stopping that yeah for sure you
know that that's what always made it
click for me is just like oh it's you
performing actions by yourself but
someone else is causing you to do it
implicitly yeah yeah and and dude I I
I'm pretty sure that that example is in
literally every piece of c-surf
Education literature out there so I
wonder if that ever happened like I
wonder if the person that created you
know or invented sea surface like 2002.
yeah it's like I can make what if I
force the user let me let me log into my
bank and see if this works you know like
yeah and that's like the original
write-up you know it's like passing
around material on the dark web like for
bank.com you can trick you know trigger
transfers I don't know why that's my
voice for early day hackers like maybe
the early 2000s yeah exactly like I
don't know but
um yeah that would be interesting uh
okay so everything was fine and dandy
for years we were finding sea surf's uh
as they're affectionately named left and
right
um and then one fateful day the same
site cookie default lacks setting was
imposed by chromium the you know Monster
browser that destroys all of our hopes
and dreams
um and since then it has been a lot
trickier to do that and the reason for
that is is that same-site cookies uh are
uh any cookie that's set now is being
explicitly set to or implicitly excuse
me set to
um
lack same site lacks by default what
that means is that there's only a very
there's a very specific set of
conditions that must be completed
um before you can trigger a a request to
be with those cookies to be sent
um those conditions are uh that you have
to be making a top level navigation
um so that means that you essentially
the URL bar up at the top has to be
um changing in order for those cookies
to be sent it can only be done with a
get in a post request and with the post
request it can only be done within a two
minute window of that cookie being set
that is called The Lax plus post
um sort of caveat it's a temporary thing
we don't know how long it's going to
last I think it's probably going to last
for a while
um but that that even may may fade and
fail us
um so that's really interesting behavior
that it's like it feels almost very
arbitrary that it's a two minute window
yeah and that it just kind of works
because what happens like after
like say that happens in the first five
seconds right okay what about the other
minute in 55 seconds yeah yeah yeah I I
think I think it you know it was just
sort of a catch-all for very slow
loading single sign-on Services
um so I'm not exactly sure you know why
they they chose two minutes arbitrarily
um but I do think it's a cool I think
it's a cool uh technique and if you can
still use it it's very helpful for this
technique I don't you've probably seen
this before but exploding that where you
trigger a login or re-login right and
what that will do is get the cookie
reset right
um and and even if you know the user has
already got an established session this
can be done oftentimes with a get
request and a window.open right and then
once the cookie is reset that timer's
got refreshed and then you can do a top
level post
um which will trigger the C serve so
it's very important nowadays if you're
going to try to find a post-based c-surf
to have some sort of Gadget which will
refresh the session get that cookie
reset so that you can take advantage of
the LAX plus post window
yeah yeah that's uh that's really
interesting I mean it's not like the
biggest Walker but it is kind of like an
additional part of the chain that you
now have to be aware of and and I think
if you were coming from a more
traditional background and you just went
to export a CSR if you'd be like why
isn't this working and I think it's just
because it's like there's new there's
new levels that are now at play here
yeah for sure and so go go do you see
this link that I put in there um by
Teddy Katz you see that uh yes yeah
click on that really quick we can talk
through this phone I think this one's
really cool
um so I wanna so before we jump into
that I I'm gonna go ahead and talk about
the conditions for the modern conditions
the the the now conditions for a SC Surf
right
um and those are this the content type
must be text plane
xww form URL encoded or multi-part form
data one of those three right there
might be other ones I I feel like I've
seen Text slash Json being used before
NSC surf I could be wrong about that and
we're not talking about any of this
flash stuff that you can do with flash
that's that's outdated no one uses that
anymore
um so it must be one of those three the
request must be a get or a post request
and it must be a top level navigation so
the the URL bar at the top needs to
change as a result
um and that will result in the the
cookies being sent under the same site
under the the rule of this cruel cruel
you know Monarch the the same type
cookie
um the exception to that is this is this
cool blog post that I linked here so
let's take a look at that
yeah the uh this is by Teddy cats yeah
dude this guy is on his blog about get
GitHub oauth
um bypass
yeah so this guy is pretty much
exclusively a a GitHub hacker as far as
I can see and I just freaking loved this
bug so
um did you get a chance to see it before
the the Pod or am I am I preaching to
you as well dude I think I've actually
I feel like I read this a long time ago
because I've hacked GitHub since this
blog post came out in in the years since
this has come out and so I feel like I
have seen something along the lines of
this but I don't know if I've read it
specifically so go ahead you're not
totally dude I feel I feel kind of bad
because like I I do this thing where
I go to people's blogs before life
hacking event that are like really good
at hacking the Target that we're gonna
hack and I just read all of them right
like very fresh right very fresh in my
memory and twice in 2022
I found wolves and and the people that
wrote about those that using the
techniques from those blogs and the
people that wrote those Vlogs duped to
me so I I got the main report they got
the duper stealing their tickets and
they're like bro I should never have
blogged about this which is very which
is very sad you know because it's like
we do like to see sharing in the
community and stuff but also like you
know can't hey what is it what do they
say don't hate the Playa hate the game
hate that yeah yeah hate the game don't
hate the player something like that yeah
um all right so yeah this this specific
one pretty cool
uh I will link it it's called bypassing
githubs uh oauth flow this is an example
of c-surf that does not use get or post
this is a uh c-surf done with a head
request
um which was which was really
interesting to me
um essentially the tldr of this is that
the
get the head request gets routed to the
same spot in the application
um I want to say this is is this rails
yeah it's real yeah it's rails so the
the way that the rails router is defined
it says you know match the specific path
and then there's
um via and then you provide a list of uh
uh you know valid
um
uh HTTP
I couldn't come up with it yeah you
provide get imposed
um and then so there's just get in post
in this array in the blog post but
um there's also some Quirk and rails
where they just want head to kind of
work seamlessly they don't want you to
have to be able to have to like you know
work on head being something different
than get
right so head also gets routed to
wherever get is is routed to
and inside super interesting yeah I
thought so too and inside the request
um it's you know inside the function
that deals with this route it it there's
this uh if statement that says if the
request if request.get then do this
right otherwise do that
so it's not checking you know it's a
pretty safe to be honest like I would
have definitely not caught this in code
review because it's like okay get only
get in poster allowed but uh and we've
got get so the only alternative can be
post right but that's not quite the case
the head method can also
um trigger this and it actually in this
case it was triggering the same thing as
a post request would do which allowed
for the um the oauth bypass uh which
landed him a pretty sick back I think
there was a 25k Bounty right 25k yeah
yeah yeah it was yeah that's really
interesting um honestly I would have
expected that
a head requests would behave more like a
get request than a post request so I
would have expected it exactly if it was
going to be an implicit thing like this
it would go through the get Handler but
uh you know maybe it was actually you
know coming through his like
request.head or something so if you look
at that it was if it's request.get yeah
and then else is catching everything
else and so it doesn't even have to be
behaving like a post request it's just
if it's not a get request then it does
this alternative Behavior which would be
to Grant permissions
I wonder if options does the same thing
yeah I assume it probably does because
head and options are special cases right
where those are really meant for the
browser to do pre pre-check requests and
that kind of stuff to make sure that the
endpoints exist or are reachable and
that kind of stuff right yeah I thought
the same thing before I you know while
prepping for this episode and I looked
into it and I think options at least
normally they're sent by the browser
without any
um authentication attached to them I
I'll have to double check on that uh
because this is a while back but
um if they are sent with uh
authentication attached to them that
could be a really interesting way to
potentially exploit some of this
Behavior
yeah I would imagine that the browser
won't be sending it now but maybe they
have to you know because maybe like an
optional options request would fail if
it doesn't have the right authentication
on it I don't really know yeah
um but that might be an interesting area
to to Target for sure yeah so this is
also just a good I feel like this is
just a good Quirk to to know about in
rails as well is is that head will get
routed to the same point place that get
will and if there is this sort of you
know if get else do this sort of
mentality then this bug could very well
I I absolutely anticipate that this bug
has is present in other code bases as
well
yeah yeah I mean it's Gotta Be I I can't
imagine that
um
I mean Ruby is very very commonly used
and this seems like a strange type of
implicit behavior for it to be there
yeah so I wouldn't be surprised if it
has other implications as you can tell
in the blog post this is actually down
to how GitHub is implementing it right
where it's not really like in implicit
vulnerability it's just that the fact
that how they're handling whether or not
it's a get request or some other type of
request is influencing the behavior of
the app and so if there's other services
that are written in rails that aren't
doing an explicit check for a head or an
options or if they're doing some sort of
fallback Behavior like this is then
you'd be able to exploit that in the
same way yeah yeah I totally agree so
just as a as a as a takeaway you know
list a couple takeaways here rails uh
definitely play around with head
requests for that
um 4C surf you need to have content type
text plane X form uh xw formula encoded
or multi-part it needs to be get a post
or ahead likely request and it must be a
top level navigation that's kind of
interesting to me though because this
was before now that I'm saying all this
together this was before same-site
cookies this was 2019. so I'm wondering
if head requests
I'm wondering if that even works anymore
because I don't know that you can send a
head request via top level navigation so
how would you get the cookie
to send
yeah I wonder it might have to be
coupled with a yeah it might have to be
coupled with a uh with a like insecure
configuration for same site or something
like that in order to actually get this
to work
yeah yeah because when did same set come
out that was like 2020
um yeah February 4th 2020
stab at the heart man
yeah super interesting
um yeah so those are the takeaways there
um
let's talk a little bit about some
exploitation techniques and then we'll
kind of jump
um I mean do you have anything you want
to talk about for mobile c-surf uh I'm
not I'm not sure if you're where I guess
carf as we affectionately named it
yeah so a lot of the stuff we talked
about during the mobile app
um
episode but I think
generally it's the same kind of stuff
that you'd already be looking for so
JavaScript Bridges
expose URL schemas if there is any kind
of internal webview the non-exposed URL
schemas are also a good Target for that
because if you can find some way to
point the internal webview to an
arbitrary URL then you can potentially
exploit those internal URL schemas that
would be only accessible from within the
app and you may be able to escalate that
further to do who knows what but uh that
that I'll actually talk a little bit
about that when we talk about our
specific bugs because the specific bug I
have is very similar to that sweet solid
well we'll wait for that then
um let me so I I wrote down a bunch of
exploitation techniques here let's just
kind of roll through them one by one
um oh well actually okay okay actually
before we get into this section I do
want to add one more thing about same
site
um if you if you have any
um questions or concerns about same site
uh definitely check out the Jew Bob's
post the great same-site confusion we've
talked about on the Pod several times
before really good stuff
um
the uh so on the note of same site
though there is this thing same site
strict which is rare but I actually have
seen it and I've got a funny story about
it dude actually so did you meet did you
meet uh so sakaguchi did you meet one of
my one of my friends that was from Japan
that I feel like you might have met him
in Vegas or in uh Austin
yeah I wasn't at either of the Las Vegas
or Austin events so if you were in Vegas
weren't you no I I was supposed to come
but then I had to cancel last minute
because I had to think Kevin oh heck man
well yes you might not have you might
not have met him then but you was he one
of the people that flew over and and
stayed with you yeah yeah so okay so we
were hacking together yeah he's one of
my friends from Japan
um
great hacker now I was training him you
know with some stuff and there's this
there's this app that I guess I can't
specify
um and it looks very vulnerable to
c-surf right but here's the thing it
deletes your account and he actually
uses the app
so I had like so we caught the request
right we caught the request in in verb
and we're like okay you know like look
there's no you know c-serve tokens
there's no there's no origin checks or
it doesn't look like there's an Argent
attack I guess you can't know until you
submit it
um and but you know it looks good and we
found other bugs that look similar to
this in the past on that on that website
so I was like okay man like here's the
deal we gotta
we gotta just build the POC and give it
a shot like this is a several thousand
dollar bug here like and oh and and the
the process for creating an account was
really long and hard and had a hat
required phone numbers and all sorts of
books right okay yeah so we can really
just create another account
so so we we we run the exploit on his
account it's fully expecting to be
getting you know to hear hearing noises
and
um
and I don't know how it ended up you
know being this way but uh they had same
site strict right so we we deleted his
account with something else uh you know
to try to prove it you know that the
origin check wasn't working it's like
okay great you know this is good and we
go back to do it again with another
account and the same site strict cookies
they have same-site strict on which
means that there's that you will never
it will never send a cookie to a from
one site to another site there's no not
a get request not a request it just
doesn't happen right and so at the end
it wasn't vulnerable to to see serpent
we deleted his whole account
yeah no it's so bad it was on a music
app that was that that was popular
um that where he lives so I felt really
bad man uh yeah it's funny because I was
actually looking back at um
I did have like a really low impact csrf
that I reported like many many years ago
and it was
like I don't even think I tested it like
in the traditional way because same site
wasn't a thing right so all I did was
check if I set origin to null then does
it work yes and like it redirected me to
an arbitrary domain well if there's no
if there's no um you know if there's no
other checks if there's no referred
check if there's which can be
circumvented if there's no you know
c-surf tokens in the request you'd think
it would be you know right but right all
right yeah vulnerable but not
exploitable you know yeah exploitation
techniques so
um just a couple things I just want to
note on this you know these are just
kind of pro tips section on c-surf look
at the same site values for your cookies
okay so one thing that I will I will
notice Joel did you just literally just
OCD yeah listen I'm sorry what is wrong
with you so literally in the dock I
wrote this excited no you're getting
called out for that dude I literally
wrote same site with no capitalization
and no dash in the middle in the notes
and while we're talking about lowercase
word same site so Joel goes in here and
it capitalizes it and adds the dash like
a total Maniac
um I was like look now I know that it's
it's safe now it's same size same site
you know some sight
um but yeah so the tip that I was going
to say with this is make sure you're
checking your cookies
um
note that same site if same site is not
set if the same side attribute is not
set on a cookie then that will be same
site lacks by default which is different
than same site lacks explicit okay
same site lacks explicit when it's
explicitly set
um does is not subject to The Lax plus
post
um sort of accommodation that they've
made for people transitioning because if
you're setting it explicitly then
obviously you're not one of the people
that's transitioning to a architecture
that supports this so that can be a
gotcha that can get you some Nas or some
informatives if you don't check that
um so yeah keep an eye on that
um let's um yeah another thing was the
method params
um I've seen this a lot on Ruby
especially uh there's like a really
weird Ruby's getting wet today yeah Ruby
Ruby's super weird I think this is
specifically some like weird rails
configuration or something but there's
like a method parameter that you can put
in the URL yeah and it will allow you to
change the method of your request even
if it's sent as a get request you can
have it send it as a like a post request
instead it gets interpreted on the back
end as like a post request and that adds
all sorts of different levels of
complexity now because you can send a
get request with the body right yeah
yeah I I'm not sure if you can make the
browser do that though can you yeah I
don't that's the one caveat is again
it's like vulnerable not exploitable
where yeah yeah I don't I'm not I'm not
sure that would be a kind of interesting
area to research because it would be it
would be but I feel like most of the
um you know routing software most of the
the web servers would
um just kind of consider those body
either just delete those body params on
a get request uh or just stick them as
they were you know a query parameter so
I'm not I'm not sure how that would get
get parsed but like you said you know
there's definitely the option of sending
a get request and then setting this
method equals post right and then having
the server parse it as a post request
that's a really good method right right
yep let me grab some water
heck I'm out of water
um yeah I'm just gonna cough into the
mic real quick here
um yeah this is how we know when we need
to wrap up the episodes is like Justin's
out of water his third is dying
um
yeah so let me look at some of these
other uh yeah so obviously you know get
you you want to be looking for any get
based requests that will
um result in some change in the
application right because if you have
that you're pretty much just set anyway
unless they're setting some weird you
know header or something like that
um so be on the lookout for that
um and then the other the other thing
which we alluded to earlier is I feel
like
and this is sort of I'm gonna release
something else on the Pod about this
later but I I feel like not enough
people when they look at applications
are keeping in mind various gadgets that
they need right these are parts of
chains these are links in your chain
that that you need to find so for
example if you hack all day and you
don't find anything you can feel like
garbage right or you can look back and
you can say okay well now I know that if
I go to this specific area of the
application I'll get this error error
that will tell me you know this about
the application or if I provide a valid
ID here an invalid ID then it allows me
to validate which IDs are are you know
valid or not valid or I found this
endpoint that I can force the user to
refresh their session cookie right
that's the most applicable in the
scenario those gadgets are very valuable
so even if you haven't found a bug make
sure you're noting down these gadgets
and those if you are and you're keeping
those in the front of your mind your
your brain will figure out a way to
utilize these and figure out a way to
chain these into to
um you know different bugs if you're
skipping over them if you're not
emphasizing these then uh you know
you're never just gonna get the full
chain into play so that's another that's
another tip that sort of Gadget based
methodology
yeah for sure and we've talked about
like notes you need to take notes yeah
just like if you find something that's
weird or or strange Behavior probably
not like quite a bug but could be used
with something else to become a bug
either like ID leaks anything like that
if you they're using a uuid and you find
something at least leaks a list of uuids
that's a great thing that you can chain
together as like a gadget where by
itself maybe it's not the most severe
thing but if you can then find an idler
that uses that ID that makes it so much
more severe yeah um so anything that's
like along that those lines just be
keeping notes of the different like
weird behaviors that you're seeing and
this is about
as we say becoming intimate with the
applications man it is you know you this
is part of the process of understanding
how does the application work what are
the different moving Parts what are the
different functionalities that exist is
one
specific part not secure that can then
be used with another specific part
that's not secure to then leverage that
further
um those are the types of things that we
really want to look for yeah yeah for
sure
I I think yeah yeah and so there's lots
of different ways that you can
um approach these these vulnerabilities
these you know these applications that
you're trying to find
um and and we're not trying to say you
know everyone needs to take notes
everyone needs to keep in mind uh the
gadgets but that's something that's
definitely worked worked for me quite a
bit
um in the past and I think it's helpful
methodology
um let's see let's see what else we got
here
um okay well this is an interesting one
so if you and when we've tweeted about
this a little bit as well when rezo
mentioned something like this but one of
the main ways that I find Sea surf
nowadays is servers that are using just
plain Json requests and
um you know you nor as we know Json as a
content type is not vulnerable to
cross-site request forgery however
excuse me
however if you um if you change the
content type from Json to text plane or
for to X WWE form URL encoded
um then it may be vulnerable it could be
that the server is parsing that content
type or if you're sending text plain it
could just consider that as Json so
those are good areas to check um it
normally only takes one or two different
checks because
I guess maybe this is my experience I
won't Prime you otherwise but in my
experience you know I don't check every
single endpoint for this I check like
one or two endpoints for this to see if
like you know the server actually just
at all just does not mess with uh you
know xww formula encoded or textplane
um I don't test all of them but I could
be missing some there so I I you know
whatever testing style fits you best as
long as you're checking if you can
convert content types
yeah for sure I you know I think it's
if you think about it from a developer's
perspective it's probably going to be
implemented in like one place so it's
going to be added as a middleware or a
content type Handler for the entire
server exactly versus being on an end
point by end point basis because usually
it's being processed at a lower level
than it is
like at the route Handler it's probably
going to be on the server level so I
think your testing methodology there
probably makes sense to just like see if
this host is vulnerable to that type of
confusion or changing of types and see
if it's flexible in that way of parsing
and then if it's not I wouldn't waste
too much time
I think it's really interesting to think
about how csrf is one of the more like
old school type of vulnerabilities
because the way that it gets exploited
is still using a form element you know I
mean it's not like yeah anything crazy
it's not like custom modern jsr it's
literally just a form you know it's just
a form HTML element and so you do get
restricted by some of those bounds in
terms of how a form element actually
works what capabilities it has what
content type it is how it encodes data
all that kind of stuff which is why it
needs to be either text plane or form
URL encoded because
forms don't send Json
um right and apps that are sending Json
are typically JavaScript based where
you're clicking a button and that's
triggering an on click Handler which is
then making a fetch requests or whatever
it is in the back end that's actually
triggering the API request versus
sending a a very you know traditional
HTML form yeah yeah and and I I like
what you said about HTML sort of being
limited by by old HTML in that capacity
because they we do still exploit c-surfs
um via form elements and I'm looking
right now you can set the content type
on a form element using the ENC type
attribute and the method by the method
attribute I'm a little salty because I
went and looked into this at ANC type
um uh attribute the other day and it
would be really cool if we could
specify not only the content type but
the character
encoding in here as well you know
because you could do because we were
looking into this is a little bit of a
rabbit Trail but we were looking into
bypassing wafts you know payloads um
using encoding I think uh surush tweeted
something out about that
um and we were just kind of going back
and forth on it I was like man I wonder
if we can force the browser to send a
request using
um utf-7 or something like that right
um and I was thinking man that the ENC
type should ENC type should do it and I
think even the HTML spec mentions that
it should be able to do it but it
freaking doesn't do it man that is salty
well I mean this wouldn't be the first
time where the HTML specs is one thing
and every single thing on the internet
says that the spec follows this one
thing and it doesn't so maybe uh maybe
it's worth looking into and actually
verifying honestly since that thing that
we found with the bass element yeah it
really has me wondering how much of HTML
is strictly enforced to what the spec
says it should be yeah and how much
flexibility there is in in terms of
weird edge cases and stuff like this
yeah I'm sure there's tons
um just more and more to uncover
um so the the other couple a couple
other little things I had here um
obviously making sure you're changing
your post request to get request it's
one of the I I pretty much forced kaido
to do that
um uh because I told them like hey I
like this is one of the main features I
use in burp you know this change request
functionality so they did put it into
kaido which is great
um and so converting your post request
to your get request makes it really easy
to to check
um
and then uh so the other thing that I
kind of wanted to mention was sometimes
they'll companies will do sneaky stuff
like check the origin header and check
the refer header to ensure to further
see surf checks and those is technically
proper c-serv protection that plus a
c-serve token is really I believe the
recommendation it can release it was it
can be there is there is ways there are
there is ways there are ways to bypass
that
um so for the origin uh and I guess if
it's configured properly there's not
ways to bypass it but for the origin you
can get the origin to be set to null
for a request by doing it with in a
iframe that is the source of that iframe
the source attribute of that iframe is a
data URI
and that will remove the origin from
that from that
um iframe and allow you to just you know
run your HTML document that you've
defined inside of that that data URI
inside of there and then you can try to
trigger it that way I'm wondering now
that I'm saying it because a lot of
these techniques are are a little
Antiquated I'm wondering
that that isn't going to
that isn't going to pass the same site
checks now though right I don't I don't
know and with course
with cores and CSP you'd also get
blocked a lot of the time by
not having the right URL or not being
able to even open data URLs yeah csb I
need I need to look that up and see if
there's any way
is there yeah I'm gonna research this
any afterwards anyway to send a request
um with the null in the origin
um with nowadays same side stuff that
that's kind of interesting I I sort of
didn't apply the same side stuff in my
brain to this technique so so that's
that
um perhaps maybe An Origin check might
be enough nowadays uh you know
especially if you are
handling the null case it would
definitely be enough like like you were
saying yeah um but if you're not
handling the no case it could still be
enough because the browser may not allow
you to do it
um
the only other one was the referrer and
I was going to say this one uh this is
not as
excuse me
this is not a secure technique for a sea
surf uh because we have the ability to
control the referrer policy which
determines
um what is set right and actually oh I I
didn't even write this down Joel but I
actually had a cool bug that I that I
found the other day because of this
because oh what it was doing
um was it was sending this gosh I love
this bug I can't believe I didn't get
this in the notes for this episode
um so here's what it was I'm just going
to drop everything and tell you about it
right now okay uh so it was a sea surf
here's the season
and it was doing uh the sea surf check
via the referrer right and so I was like
okay you know easy peasy and all I was
doing it was checking to make sure that
um site uh you know site.com slash was
in the referrer so I was like okay uh
easy peasy I should just be able to
um create a folder called site you know
site.com slash and xq maxplay from there
and then that should pass the check
right
um wrong because uh you can't whenever
you're sending they deleted the referrer
parameter uh the paths from the refer
parameter nowadays right
um okay oh yeah yeah so interesting it
just sends by default it just sends you
know https uh you know the top level the
fqdn slash two crosswords I thought that
was only for ORD I thought that was only
for Origins what do you mean
I thought only origin headers did that
behavior I didn't know that refers
because that was a big problem for a
long time where API tokens and stuff
would get excuse me we get leaked
through a refer header because referrer
is the exact prefer URL whereas origin
would be just the origin URL exactly
that in and I think that's the reason
why they removed it was because because
it was lit because what you could do is
you could get an HTML injection right
with an image tag and then redirect the
user to that specific page
um you know with their access token and
URL and that access token would get
leaked by either referrer to you know
your image that you inject into the page
and your boom you got an ATL
um right but anyway they removed that
and so I bypassed it because you can
actually set the referrer policy on your
own page to send the full URL
um it doesn't have to be uh you know
since you control the the page that
you're sending from you can use it I
think it's a meta tag um you should look
that up really quick see if you can find
anything but um the The Meta tag I
believe allows you to set the referrer
policy and what and there are several
options for that one of those is send
the full URL in the referrer
um and so plop that into my page
um you know send the user to that page
and it sent the full URL which allowed
me to bypass the csurf check and got got
the bug
um so I I don't know man that that sort
of Fringe stuff like that just gets my
blood pumping I love it yeah yeah so
there's actually two ways to do it there
you can set it
um as a header refer Dash policy okay
like no referrer origin same order and
strict origin unsafe URL and then you
can also set it with HTML through a meta
tag like you thought meta the name is
refer and then the content would be like
origin for example interesting yeah I
think I'm looking at the same page that
you are yeah yeah the The Meta The Meta
tag is so interesting dude like because
because I have a lot of functional yeah
we were kind of deep diving this last
time with like you know when we were
looking into bass and stuff like that
but um this doesn't even use the HTTP
equiv attribute
um uh you know to to like pretend like
it's an HTTP header right this is
actually just a different thing so I
gotta yeah I gotta go I I gotta find
some way to just read everything that a
meta tag can do
because I'm sure there's some weird
stuff there
yeah yeah and I I'm not really sure
where the best like the right place to
look either because I feel like if even
if we look at the HTML spec it's not
really what you need to look at it's you
should probably look at like the Chrome
source code or something like dude I
don't want to look at the Chrome source
code man that hurts my eyes don't like
that yeah me neither
um cool all right so that's that's uh
yeah that's all I had for the actual
um
content of the sea surf stuff yep yeah
that's all I have you want to go into
bugs real quick yeah let's do it man
okay so I already I already presented
one bug because I just got hype I just
I love that man but this next one is
actually really cool too
so this is a sea surf that I found
um at a live hacking event in um
um and there was this obscure domain
that was way out there right that that
no you super old Legacy garbage and
there's some like weird trickery I
figured out a way to get an account on
that domain
um there's like a hidden sign up page
that was like I found in like a way back
archive thing right so I got there got
into that app and I'm like seeing dollar
signs at this point right because it's
like it was in scope too they had star
and scope so I was like oh this is
clutch and and nice I did get like you
know five figures worth of bounties
um from that specific uh domain one of
them was the sea surf which is which was
cool
um now how this one worked was it it
sort of had four parts of the chain okay
um so I needed to send two top level
requests that this this required one
click so you come to the attacks page
and it triggers one click
um
from that I could trigger two pieces of
code okay I could trigger
um there's a little hack here you can
use the the form uh the button within
the form
um you can Harvest one click and get two
actions to be triggered you can get a
form submission because the button got
clicked and you can also use the on
click so this actually allowed me to
open up two pages with one click
um nice and so the first thing that I
did was I said I see serve login
c-surfed the victim into this old Legacy
website from the main website I found a
way to do that where you can you know
transfer the user in okay then the
second request which was still pending
by the way
um that was sent to a PHP script on my
server that was set to sleep for like
two seconds or whatever right so it sort
of delays and make sure that the user is
actually authored in the website first
then it it redirects the victim I think
I had to do a 307 two because I think it
was a post request
um I had an issue at 307 which redirects
the user to it to with the same method
post method
to a different URL
um where the c-surf actually occurred
um and all this was happening
um you know when the user came to the
attackers page and and it was actually a
c-surf to affect the user's account in
that sort of weird obscure you know
domain which is not very impactful and I
thought they wouldn't like it but um the
the you know through the data pipelines
that data actually ends up back on the
main application and had some some
pretty painful effects on the main
application
um so that ended up getting accepted it
used a couple cool tricks which is why I
I mentioned it used this double sort of
on click thing and then also the delay
script I think was a nice piece as well
yeah that's super interesting that that
that aspect of
sort of the double the double action
where you click a button and you you
take advantage of the on click as well
as the native form element Behavior yeah
yeah it's an interesting little trick I
I have to refresh that in my mind
because there are definitely scenarios
where you need to to click triggered
actions
um yeah
yeah super interesting
okay so for my mine is more like uh the
kind of thing that I talk about where
it's it's basically the closest you can
get to a sea surf without it being a
carf
um
yeah so it's not cross app but it is
cross domain within the app so it's
essentially
um I think I can talk about this uh uh
yes they're public okay so Tick Tock
everybody knows Tick Tock
um uh this was way back before Tick Tock
was popular this was in 2019.
um and so Tech talk I don't know if they
still have this functionality but
essentially you could scan a QR code
within the app and that would I think
take you to somebody's profile or take
them take you to like a post or
something like that it was built in
um but the thing is that QR codes can
have a lot of different data encoded to
them right so I realized that you could
just encode an arbitrary QR code
pointing to a URL
and it would open it within the app in
the internal webview within the app
because the way that it routed was that
it would try and use the internal URL
schemas and typically it would be
encoded with some you know internal
schema that would open someone's profile
or something like that but you if you
put just HTTP in there then it'll open
it in an internet so wait so this is it
do you have to scan it within the tick
tock app or can you just scan it with
your phone you have to scan it within
app right
yeah so the attack scenario would be
like you know you open your Tick Tock
app you open scan some QR code to go to
someone's profile you get popped right
um and so basically this would open up
an internal webview that then had access
to this JavaScript bridge and a bunch of
other internal functionality that you
could then take advantage of because
typically they weren't expecting that
you would be within this context
and so there was a whole bunch of
different checks in terms of like the
functions and stuff that you could call
but there was this caveat which is that
the the if you were like calling the
JavaScript Bridge it had this check
called is safehost and it would
essentially had a list of allowed URLs
uh but the problem is that it was
checking if host.equals or host dot ends
with blank then proceed and you may have
picked up on this already but that ends
with is not safe if it was just.equals I
would have been fine but that ends with
is very very flexed that ends with and
then with no preceding dot is that
correct correct and so uh not on the
list did have sub domains however for
example ticktock.com
and so I purchased the domain not tick
tock.com nice.com
yes and it was like five dollars yeah
and so I put together a POC and
basically if you scan a URL it points to
not ticktock.com with my POC
it would open it up and then from there
because it passes the host check you're
able to talk with the JavaScript bridge
and so there was a ton of functionality
behind this once you get past that check
where you could create pop-ups within
the app you could install apks to prompt
the user you could hold down user
information about who the current user
is so there was like a ton of
functionality that you could do from
that point and that's kind of like the
c-serve aspect where it's on my post
it's on nottechdark.com but I'm talking
with the app over the JavaScript bridge
over the internal URL schemas and I'm
getting information across app that I
really shouldn't be able to so it's kind
of like cores kind of like csrf you know
um but yeah that that's kind of my
mobile example
and I think there's a a ton of other
examples out there that are more the the
carf stuff that we talked about where
it's like creating intents from a
third-party app right that then do
something similar where it's exporting
app functionality that you normally
wouldn't be able to reach unless you
were coming from a third-party app or
from some third-party standpoint
um like a you know a webview within the
app or something like that for sure that
that's a really that's a cool technique
because there there are a lot of apps
that have built-in QR code scanners so I
bet other apps that have bug batting
programs out there are vulnerable to
opening the webview Via QR code like
that right with just a you know a domain
and you might have to sort of double
click into the code a little bit to see
if there are like a An Origin check or
something like that
um but dude I love I love those moments
when you get in there and you're like
gosh shoot there's an origin check like
ah I'm in trouble and you look at it
it's like ends with and you're like
nevermind I love that yeah exactly
exactly man it just freaking yeah gets
the blood pumping yeah um yeah so don't
uh you know if you see something look
look into it fully until you're for sure
that it can't be exploited because uh
lots of times there'll be weird checks
like that good stuff man
um all right anything else we wanna we
wanna cover before we wrap up today
um oh yes one thing so you may have seen
on Twitter nahomsek Ben our buddy he is
on his way he's very very close to a
hundred thousand subscribers on YouTube
yeah
um so I think he's let me double check
where his actual number is but yeah I
think he was at like 95k 94k 95k so he
has a goal he'd love to hit 100K before
Defcon and if he does he's gonna shave
his whole beard he's gonna shave his
whole head dude he's gonna be hairless
dude I wonder if we can get him to do
the eyebrows too
yeah maybe eyebrows too so definitely if
you aren't already go check out nahom
sex channel it's at nahomsek on YouTube
and uh give him a subscription he's
pumping out amazing content he live
streams he has so much insightful stuff
kind of similar to the stuff that we do
but like on another level and uh yeah
definitely definitely would recommend
going and I'm looking at his channel
again that's the call to action for
today y'all you know today subscribe to
Ben go to nahom sex Channel hit that
subscribe button we want to see a bald
in in eyebrow list so
please do that for us yeah it's actually
a win-win for Ben right because he gets
he gets um you know he's got like 100k
subscribers right so he's like you know
pretty well known and I'm sure if he
goes to Defcon people are gonna be like
ah now I'm sick you know awesome but you
know let's get a picture together or
something like that right so if he if he
does get up to 100K subscribers then he
gets 100K subscribers and he also gets
to shave his head and his beard and his
eyebrows and No One's Gonna notice him
so he can just kind of you know skate
around uh you know Defcon like he's not
famous
yeah yeah and then all the photos will
be great memories of yeah oh that's true
but the people that do recognize him
will have a Priceless photo forever
exactly exactly it's like a limited
edition
dude not a good year for me to skip
Defcon heck yeah yeah you're really busy
now but I understand there's uh there
are more important life events there are
yes for sure yeah all right with that
that's a wrap yeah
yep that's about peace peace
foreign
[Music]